Fletcher School Records UA015
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Fletcher program theses, 1981 -- 2015; UA015.012; 286 Digital Object(s); 1 Volumes
  - Locating Legitimacy in Territorial Space, 2004; UA015.012.DO.00149; Renert, Joey
    Submitted in partial fulfillment of the degree Master of Arts in Law and Diplomacy at the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy. Abstract: When human governing systems are compared to those of the natural world, the natural world appears very stable by comparison. The rise and fall of civilizations, empires and states is at the same time accompanied by unmovable forests, oceans and rivers in which vast numbers of living things interact and maintain themselves without any guidance or direction from a central authority. When looked at closely, natural systems are in fact very complex entities with many different species interacting that are constantly changing and adapting, but somehow, the system as a whole remains stable. What is it about the dynamics of nature that allows it to look like a static governing system while human dynamics produce unstable governing systems? Is there some natural characteristic that results in natures stable systems that can be replicated to better create more stable human governing systems? This paper proposes the idea that, like natural systems, human governance systems can be defined as Complex Adaptive Systems, and that the key feature distinguishing human rule making from nature is legitimacy. Legitimacy itself will be shown as an emergent property of the human governance system and it is generated through the physical interaction of people in geographic space.
    MALD thesis; Political Systems and Theories; Legitimacy of governments; Complex adaptive systems
  - 'History Obliges' The Real Motivations Behind German Aid Flows in the Case of Namibia, 2004; UA015.012.DO.00150; Schuring, Esther
    Submitted in partial fulfillment of the degree of Master of Arts in Law and Diplomacy at the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy. Abstract: This study explains the exceptional donor position that Germany assumes in Namibia. Contrary to the predominant discourse on aid allocation literature, this study finds that classic motives such as need, economic potential, strategic interest in military terms, democracy and region do not factor in as strongly in Namibia's case. Germany's aid flows are largely a result of two variables, (1) moral obligation, a largely understudied variable and (2) cultural similarity, a variable not often applied in the German context due to the removed colonial presence. Moral obligation is mainly a product of German-Namibian colonial history -the 'genocide' that the emperor's troops executed in 1904-07, reinforced by the largely contested German aid flows to Namibia during South African occupation. The recognition of colonial wrongdoings by German politicians, coupled with external pressure have turned moral obligation into the most decisive variable in the German-Namibian aid relationship. Whereas internal pressure has been almost non-existent, external pressure has been exerted continuously and successfully by the Namibian government and by the Herero. Worried about its reputation and costly reparations, the German government appears to have used its generous aid flows in an attempt to silence these pressure sources. The second most influential variable, the cultural similarity to the 20,000 Namibia Germans, has political as well as sentimental roots: German politicians have cared and continue to do so for their constituency in Namibia and in no other country, the German language and traditions play such a significant role as in Namibia. Next to these two prevalent variables, a third variable has increasingly gained more momentum. Although not one of the predominant determinants of German aid flows, the socio-political strategic interest of the German government to placate potential tensions arising from the land reform issue has guaranteed that aid continues to flow. This variable is a combination of moral obligation (land reform as colonial legacy) and cultural similarity (concern about the well-being of the Namibia Germans).
  - 'Fine-Tuning the Marine Corps' Counterinsurgency Capabilities, 2004; UA015.012.DO.00151; Ruvalcaba, Jaime
    Submitted in partial fulfillment of the degree of Master of Arts in Law and Diplomacy at the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy. No abstract available.
  - State Branding in the 21st Century, 2004; UA015.012.DO.00152; De Vicente, Jorge
    Submitted in partial fulfillment of the degree of Master of Arts in Law and Diplomacy at the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy. Abstract: none
- Anniversaries and commemorations, 1975 -- 2015; UA015.013; 0.5 Linear Feet; 6 Digital Object(s)
  This series consists of materials produced for various anniversaries and commemorations of the Fletcher School.
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  - 50th Anniversary Proclamation by Governor Michael S. Dukakis, 1984; UA015.013.078.00001 (Box 78)
  - 50th Anniversary Resolution by the Massachusetts House of Representatives, 1984; UA015.013.078.00002 (Box 78)
  - 75th Anniversary Celebration program, 2008 -- 2010; UA015.013.078.00003 (Box 78)
    Donated by Anne Sauer.
  - 75th Anniversary scarf, 2008; UA015.013.078.00004 (Box 78)
  - 75th Anniversary speech by John C. Perry, 2008; UA015.013.078.00005; Perry, John; Faculty Reflections.
  - 75th Anniversary speech by Joel Trachtman, 2008; UA015.013.078.00006; Trachtman, Joel; Faculty Reflections. 'The Task of Diplomacy Tomorrow: An Essay Commemorating James T. Shotwell's Address given at the Formal Opening of The Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy in 1933'.
  - 75th Anniversary speech by Dahlia Shaham, 2008; UA015.013.078.00007; Shaham, Dahlia; Student Remarks.
  - 75th Anniversary speech by Brian Neff, 2008; UA015.013.078.00008; Shaham, Dahlia; Alumnus Remarks.
  - 50th Anniversary program materials, 1984; UA015.013.078.00009 (Box 78)
    Received from Ginn Library, Spring 2011 (2011.111)
  - History of the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy: the First Fifteen Years, brochure supplement, 1975; UA015.013.078.00010 (Box 78)
    Original brochure was created in 1948 with the expanded supplement written a few years later.
  - John Perry Goodbye Lecture, 2015; UA015.013.00001; Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object containing 1 file.; 1.44 Gigabytes
    Goodbye lecture given by Professor John Perry at the Fletcher School on May 15, 2015.
    Transferred by the Fletcher School, 2017, accession UA-2017-058.
- 2016 accessions, circa 1980 -- 2010; UA015.014; 8.4 Linear Feet 7 record cartons
  University records are closed for 20 years from the date of creation. Records older than 20 years that do not pertain to student education, staff and faculty employment and Board of Trustees records are open for research.
  Transferred by the Office of Development and Alumni Relations of the Fletcher School, 2016, accession UA-2017-004.
  This series is arranged in received order. Box titles provided by department.
  This series contains files of the Office of Development and Alumni Relations at the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy, and includes material related to funds, fellowships, scholarships, and internships, as well as other office files. Box titles provided by department.
  - Department of Defense-Public Service Fellowships General, circa 1980 -- 2010; UA015.014.085; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 85)
    20 years from date of creation.
  - General Endowment Funds, circa 1980 -- 2010; UA015.014.086; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 86)
  - Measher Fund-Starr Internship, circa 1980 -- 2010; UA015.014.087; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 87)
  - Humphrey Fellows-Stewart Library Funds, circa 1980 -- 2010; UA015.014.088; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 88)
  - Hill Scholarship-Tuck Memorial Fellowship, circa 1980 -- 2010; UA015.014.089; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 89)
  - Prize Funds, Library Chairs, Endowed Funds, circa 1980 -- 2010; UA015.014.090; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 90)
  - Class of '64 Fellowship-Henderson Scholarship, Stewart Fellowship-Stewardship General Misc., circa 1980 -- 2010; Ua015.014.091; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 91)
- 2018 accessions, circa 1940 -- 2001; UA015.015; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list. This series may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
  This series contains endowment files related to the Murrow Center and the Murrow Center Conference at Talloires, Walter Wriston, the Hay Book Fund, and the Clayton Center.
  This series is arranged in order of accession.
  - Endowment files, circa 1940 -- 2001; UA015.015.092; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 92)
    Transferred by the Fletcher School Development Office, 2018, accession UA-2019-023.
    This box contains endowment files related to the Murrow Center and the Murrow Center Conference at Talloires, Walter Wriston, the Hay Book Fund, and the Clayton Center.
- Institute for Business in the Global Context records, 2013 -- 2014; UA015.016; 18 Digital Object(s); 19.7 Megabytes
  The digital working papers in this series were not arranged.
  This series is open for research.
  This series contains reports and working papers published by the Institute for Business in the Global Context (IBGC) from 2013-2014.
  - The Cost of Cash in Mexico, 2014-11; UA015.016.00001; Mazzotta, Benjamin D.; Chakravorti, Bhaskar; Burgess, Elisabeth; 1 Digital Object(s)
    Mexico
  - The Cost of Cash in India, 2014-10; UA015.016.00002; Mazzotta, Benjamin D.; Chakravorti, Bhaskar; Bijapurkar, Rama; Shukla, Rajesh; Ramesha,K; Bapat, Dhananjay; Roy, Deepankar; 1 Digital Object(s)
    India
  - The Cost of Cash in the United States, 2013-09; UA015.016.00003; Chakravorti, Bhaskar; Mazzotta, Benjamin D.; 1 Digital Object(s)
    United States
  - Cash Outlook: India, 2013-09; UA015.016.00004; Korenke, Ruben; Joseph, Nikhil; Mazzotta, Benjamin D.; 1 Digital Object(s)
  - Cash Outlook: Mexico, 2013-09; UA015.016.00005; Burgess, Elisabeth; Mazzotta, Benjamin D.; San Juan, Jose Maria; Zuccolotto Soto, Anna Valeria; 1 Digital Object(s)
  - Cash Outlook: Egypt, 2013-10; UA015.016.00006; Holmes, Melinda; Mattern,Max; Mazzotta, Benjamin D.; 1 Digital Object(s)
    Egypt
  - Telecomm-Telegrafos: Connecting the Disconnected Rural Population, 2013-10; UA015.016.00007; San Juan, Jose Maria; Valenti, Alessandra; 1 Digital Object(s)
  - Compartamos: Moving Away from a Cashless Bank Model, 2013-10; UA015.016.00008; San Juan, Jose Maria; Valenti, Alessandra; 1 Digital Object(s)
  - Payclip: a Mobile Point of Sale for the Spanish-Speaking World, 2013-10; UA015.016.00009; Zuccolotto Soto, Anna Valeria; Valenti, Alessandra; 1 Digital Object(s)
  - Explaining the Prevalence and Resilience of Cash in Egypt, 2013-09; UA015.016.00010; Warde, Ibrahim; 1 Digital Object(s)
  - Frugal Finance: How Eko Helps India's Migrants Move and Manage Money, 2014-10; UA015.016.00011; Joseph, Nikhil; Mazzotta, Benjamin D.; 1 Digital Object(s)
  - Sub-K iTransactions, 2014-10; UA015.016.00012; Durgavanshi, Siddharth S.; Mazzotta, Benjamin D.; 1 Digital Object(s)
  - Reasons and Attitudes to Using Cash in India, 2014-10; UA015.016.00013; Bijapurkar, Rama; Shukla, Rajesh; Bordoloi, Mridusmita; 1 Digital Object(s)
  - M-PESA Comes to India, 2014-10; UA015.016.00014; Joseph, Nikhil; Mazzotta, Benjamin D.; 1 Digital Object(s)
  - Citrus: India's Answer to PayPal?, 2014-10; UA015.016.00015; Joseph, Nikhil; Mazzotta, Benjamin D.; 1 Digital Object(s)
  - Following Scale with Profits: Explaining Fino's Unlinkely Success, 2014-10; UA015.016.00016; Joseph, Nikhil; Mazzotta, Benjamin D.; 1 Digital Object(s)
  - Cash and Currency Operations in India, 2014-10; UA015.016.00017; Ramesha,K; Bapat, Dhananjay; Roy, Deepankar; 1 Digital Object(s)
  - Recent Developments on Financial Inclusion in India, 2014-10; UA015.016.00018; Ramesha,K; Bapat, Dhananjay; Roy, Deepankar; 1 Digital Object(s)
- Additional accessions, UA015.017
  - Pamphlets, catalogs, reports, 1970 -- 2007; UA015-001 (Box 1)
  - Videos, 1984 -- 1985; UA015-002 (Box 2)
  - Fletcher Guest lectures DV Tapes and slides, 2003; UA015-003 (Box 3)
  - Fletcher commencement videotapes and photos, 2001-04, 2001 -- 2004; UA015-004 (Box 4)
  - Fletcher personnel files, A-Shulman, UA015-005 (Box 5)
  - Fletcher personnel files, Skolnikoff- Zymelman and various letters, UA015-006 (Box 6)
  - Magnetic Tapes (6); 5" Audio Reels (4); 7" Audio Reels (8), 1965 -- 1973; UA015-007 (Box 7)
    The contents of these boxes can be found on the Q drive\Collection Documentation\Fletcher-av-greenboxes.doc. These materials were discovered in the Murrow Collection (MS025) and should be reunited with UA015.
  - 7" Audio Reels (19), 1965 -- 1969; UA015-008 (Box 8)
  - 7" Audio Reels (18), 1965 -- 1977; UA015-009 (Box 9)
  - 7" Audio Reels (19), 1965 -- 1977; UA015-010 (Box 10)
  - 10" Audio Reels (12), 1991 -- 1992; UA015-011 (Box 11)
  - 10" Audio Reels (11), possibly blank, UA015-012 (Box 12)
  - 10" Audio Reels (12), possibly blank, UA015-013 (Box 13)
  - Honorary Degrees, Photographs, 1990 -- 1993; UA015-014 (Box 14)
  - The Edward R. Murrow Center files, 1975 -- 2008; UA015-015 (Box 15)
    Added 3 copies of ERM Memorial Conference programs on 2008-08-04 (accession 2009.006)
  - Fletcher School publications, event brochures and records, and alumni directories, 1960 -- 1990; UA015-016 (Box 16)
    Includes some items from 1940. Added accession 2009.029 to box on 2008-10-09 vam.
  - Fletcher School publications, event brochures and records, and alumni directories, 1960 -- 1990; UA015-017 (Box 17)
    Course bulletins, brochures, and publications added to this box May 4, 2007. They were previously stored with other unknown accessions in the stacks without a green barcode. Posters, flyers and pamphlets regarding Iraq added May 11, 2007. Bulletin for the Fletcher School (1938-39) and Murrow Center Pamphlet (1970-71) added October 31, 2007 (2008.028)
  - Fletcher School scrapbook, 1960; UA015-018 (Box 18)
  - Fletcher School Commencement Photos, 1986 -- 2001; UA015-019 (Box 19)
    photographic media
  - Fletcher School Commencement Photos, Videos, Tapes, 1990 -- 2002; UA015-020 (Box 20)
    photographic media also includes analog AV media
  - Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy, Ginn Library Photos, UA015-021 (Box 21)
  - Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy, Ginn Library Photos, UA015-022 (Box 22)
  - CD, Book signing 1, 2006-07-27; UA015-023
    Electronic media. Physical media housed in 39090014011098g.
  - Fletcher Class Day, Commencement and Program DVDs and Videos, 2005 -- 2007; UA015-025 (Box 23)
  - Fletcher School Pamphlets, Catalogs, and Handbooks, 1978 -- 2007; UA015-026 (Box 24)
    Bulk dates 2000-07
  - Fletcher School Photographs, 1997 -- 2007; UA015-027 (Box 25)
    print Added Fletcher new students (Fall 2007) picture to box on 2008-04-22. vam
  - Fletcher School Photographs, 1997 -- 2002; UA015-028 (Box 26)
    print
  - CDs Book signing 2, July 2007, 2006 -- 2007; UA015-029
    electronic media Physical media housed in 39090014011098g
  - Benjamin J. Cohen files, 1980; UA015-030 (Box 27)
  - 2008 incoming class photos and Bosworth Tribute Video, 2008 -- 2013; UA015-031 (Box 28)
    Photos added to box 2008-11-06. Video added 2013-05-17.
  - Annual Reports and Committee minutes, 1960 -- 1970; UA015-033 (Box 29)
    Materials found uncataloged in Room 002 of DCA storage by Susanne Belovari, August 2009. Veronica Martzahl conducted basic stabilization (removal of rust staples/paperclips and removal of hanging file folders) on 2009-09-15.
  - Reports, 1969 -- 1980; UA015-034 (Box 30)
    Materials found uncataloged in Ballou Hall vault, July 2010.
  - Fletcher School Publications, 1975 -- 2008; UA015-035 (Box 31)
  - Institute for Foreign Policy Analysis, Inc. Publications, 1978 -- 1980; UA015-036 (Box 32)
  - Summer Sessions, 1969 -- 2013; UA015-037; Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy (Box 33)
  - Alumni class "yearbooks," news articles, and recollections from alumni, 2004 -- 2014; UA015-038 (Box 34)
  - Student Council minutes budget forms, 2007 -- 2010; UA015-039 (Box 35)
  - Alfred Rubin memorial video and program, 2015-04-24; UA015-040
  - GMAP participant photos, 2005; UA015-042
    Individual and group photos of Global Master of Arts Program (GMAP) students, 2005.
  - Registrar's Office legacy materials, 1950 -- 1969; UA015-043 (Box 36)
    Assorted historical documents related to The Fletcher School, circa 1950-1970, found in the Registrar's Office by Assistant Registrar Halley Goldman. Materials may have been compiled by former Registrar Phyllis Webber.
- Web crawls, 2010; UA015.003018; 9 Web sites
  A collection of 9 websites crawled by DCA to document the now-defunct blogs associated with the Fletcher School. The websites in this series were crawled on an one-time basis.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Archived websites can be viewed online using the Internet Archive's Wayback Machine.
  - Admissions Blog, 2010-06-16 -- 2010-06-17; UA015.003019; 1 Web sites
  - Announcements Blog, 2010-06-16 -- 2010-06-17; UA015.003020; 1 Web sites
  - Calendar, 2010-06-16 -- 2010-06-17; UA015.003021; 1 Web sites
  - Fletcher Internship Blog, 2010-06-16 -- 2010-06-17; UA015.003022; 1 Web sites
  - Fletcher Podcasts, 2010-06-16 -- 2010-06-17; UA015.003023; 1 Web sites
  - Fletcher Travels, 2010-06-16 -- 2010-06-17; UA015.003024; 1 Web sites
  - FLETCHERReflections, 2010-06-16 -- 2010-06-17; UA015.003025; 1 Web sites
  - The Fletcher School - Tufts University - News & Media, 2010-06-16 -- 2010-06-17; UA015.003026; 1 Web sites
  - The Fletcher School Renovation Project, 2010-06-16 -- 2010-06-17; UA015.003027; 1 Web sites
- 2020 accessions, 2004 -- 2018; UA015.003028; Gittleman, Sol, 1934-; 3.54 Megabytes; 39 Digital Object(s)
  Transferred by Fletcher School staff, 2018, accession UA-2020-051.
  This series contains records from the Fletcher Summer School Program.
  - Fletcher Summer School Program records, 2004 -- 2018; UA015.003029
    This material contains Fletcher Summer School advertising material, faculty CVs and syllabi, statistics related to the Summer School program and finances, and Institutional Review Board (IRB) templates.